<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE rss PUBLIC "-//Netscape Communications//DTD RSS 0.91//EN" "http://my.netscape.com/publish/formats/rss-0.91.dtd">
<rss version="0.91">
  <channel>
    <title>Advogato</title>
    <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/</link>
    <description>Recent Advogato articles</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <title>Joe Celko on the Digital Divide</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/586.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Joe Celko questions both the existence and the importance of the &quot;Digital Divide&quot; in America today.  Saith he: 
&lt;blockquote&gt;
If having a PC is &quot;absolutely essential to preserving civil rights and truly democratic processes in this country,&quot; then what were we doing before cheap computing? I thought the Constitution was written on parchment, not a Web site.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on voting machine fraud</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/585.html</link>
      <description>I've been having a ponder on some of the problems of systematic voting fraud and came up with a suggestion. Since its not an academically rigorous approach and I don't make voting machines I thought it might be interesting to throw it at people who might care
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which technical skills are in demmand?</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/584.html</link>
      <description>Ever wonder which skills and keywords result in the most employment search engine hits?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who's working (and who's not)</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/583.html</link>
      <description>David Isenberg's latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://isen.com/ &quot;&gt;SMART letter&lt;/a&gt; includes a rather disturbing set of two emails, one from a YAUE (yet another unemployed engineer) and one from inside AT&amp;T where apparently there aren't enough qualified people left on staff to actually roll out the backlogs orders.  David speculates, &quot;&lt;i&gt;Imagine 
the unleashed progress if the existing telecom workforce were 
working up to its potential without being (a) laid off or 
(b) impeded by organizations that are desperately trying to 
defend their obsolete businesses!&lt;/i&gt;&quot; and &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; causes me to speculate, of the people regularly online here on Advogato, how many of us fall into one or both of those categories?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting a Windows port from a Unix/Linux point of view</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/582.html</link>
      <description>I am the lead developer for &lt;a href=&quot;/proj/XPLC/&quot;&gt;XPLC&lt;/a&gt;, working mainly in a Linux (or at least, Unix) environment. One of the goals of XPLC is portability, and while we haven't ported to a great number of environments yet, we maintain a Windows port to keep us honest, figuring that things are different enough in Windows, but I have been facing a number of problems that I am sure others have encountered before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A framework for Open Source projects</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/581.html</link>
      <description>I recently completed my masters thesis &lt;a href=&quot;http://greg.abstrakt.ch/docs/OSP_framework.pdf&quot;&gt;A Framework for Open Source Projects&lt;/a&gt; (1.5MB PDF). By announcing it here, I hope it can be useful for someone. Feedback welcome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conditional donations to fund software development</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/580.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; Funding the development of free software is a problem.
While it is usually to the benefit of the community for free software to be
written, the cost of development often outweighs the benefit to any one
user of the software.

&lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; In this article, I propose a method of overcoming this problem using a
system of conditional donations, so that a group of users can cooperate to
fund software development without the need for altruism: this
is a system that should make sense even to penny pinching bastards! The outcome
of a small scale test of the system is also described.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priority: Documentation, Subject: Patterns, Language: Perl, Status: Failure</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/579.html</link>
      <description>Projects I work on are universally doomed to failure. Every company I work for goes out of business (note: shortsell Motorola). Failure doesn't happen in the mode one would ever suspect, which is what makes this interesting. The code is always written in a timely manner and debugged. Perhaps I'm being premature, and I'm certainly venting, but I think its curious to see how a free documentation effort can fail, joining the ranks of commercial software development efforts and every other sort of project. Deaths of past projects and companies are a different story and one less relevant to Free Software development. This is about failing to write documentation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>draft document : Good Security Practice for a Free Software release</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/578.html</link>
      <description>As everybody knows, a lot of trojaned Free Software has been found. A vast majority of them are not using OpenPGP signed checksum file. I'm currently trying to make a basic HOWTO to make a Free Software release including OpenPGP signature. This can minimize the risk (as long as the user is checking the signature ;-). Here is a draft in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foo.be/fs-release-doc/security-fsrelease.ps&quot;&gt;PS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foo.be/fs-release-doc/security-fsrelease.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt; format. 

&lt;p&gt; Don't hesitate to provide comments and feedback following your own experience of the issue. (I hope to include the chapter in the Software Release HOWTO afterwards)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-developers who fork behind your back</title>
      <link>http://www.advogato.org/article/577.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I discovered that a co-developer on one of my sourceforge-hosted projects had forked the code and was continuing to develop it in a different CVS repository without my knowledge.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
